You've learned a lot of Python so far.
到目前为止 你已经学到了很多 Python 知识
You know how to represent numerical and text data and you know
你知道如何表示数字和文本数据 你知道
how to store collections of data in lists, sets and dictionaries.
如何用列表、集合和字典来存储数据集
Yes, you've collected a set of tools for working with data.
是的 你收集了一组处理数据的工具
You can use Python's built-in methods and
你可以使用 Python 的内置方法和函数
functions and you can write functions of your own.
你可以编写自己的函数
You can iterate with loops and make conditional decisions with if and else.
你可以使用循环迭代 使用 if 和 else 进行条件选择
With these tools, you can solve most programming problems.
使用这些工具 你可以解决大部分编程问题
Sure, there's more to Python than all we've covered
当然 Python 比我们目前所涉及的更庞大
so far and we'll get two more topics later on.
我们稍后会再讲解两个主题
But now, it's time to apply the skills you've
但是 现在是应用所学技能的时候了
learned so you can practice the craft of programming.
实践才可以提高你的编程技艺
That's right. Programming is more than just syntax.
那就对了 编程可不仅仅是语法
To solve a problem you need to define it first.
要解决问题 你需要先定义它
For example, you'll need to think about inputs to
例如 你需要考虑函数的输入
the program and the results that you should give as output.
以及你应该输出的结果
Once you thought through the goals of your program,
一旦你想通了程序的目标
you need to think about how to break the program down into smaller pieces.
你需要考虑如何将程序分解成较小的部分
Then, you need to evaluate your plan to make sure it solves the original problem.
然后 你需要评估你的计划 以确保其可以解决初始的问题
I often find that when I plan a new program,
我经常发现 当我计划一个新的程序时
I realize that the problem is more complicated than I had assumed.
我意识到该问题比我假设的要复杂得多
Planning before coding, helps me understand the problem better.
编码前的规划 帮助我更好地理解问题
There are other things to keep in mind when you do begin coding.
开始编码时还要记住一些其他事项
You want to write some test cases so that you
你要写一些测试用例 以便你
can check that your code does what it's supposed to do.
可以检查你的代码是否做了它应该做的事情
You also need to make your code readable.
你还需要使你的代码可读
If your code is so complicated that you could only just understand it,
如果你的代码特别复杂 以至于你只能
as you write it, you have no hope of understanding it later on.
在你写的时候理解它 那么以后就不可能还能读懂
Before we move on to the next topics,
在我们继续讨论下一个主题之前
there will be a lab that let's you practice these skills.
会有一个实验室让你练习这些技能
Good luck. As you work,
祝你好运 当你实验的时候
remember to break problems into smaller pieces,
记得将问题分解成小块、
to plan, and to focus on readability. We'll see you soon.
计划 并注重可读性 稍后再见